帅哥  最近怎么样
Hey gorgeous, how's it going?
日光灯下吃着脱水日本方便面
Dehydrated Japanese noodles under fluorescent lights...
我现在状况比这个好点
does it get better than this?
问个问题
Question.
你目前没有约会的对象吧
You're not dating anybody, are you,
我遇见一个和你是绝配的人
because I met somebody who would be perfect for you.
绝配或许是个问题
Ah, you see, perfect might be a problem.
你若说共同独立  或自我毁灭的话
Had you said 'co- dependent', or 'self- destructive'...
周六想要有个约会的对象吗
Do you want a date Saturday?
当然拜托了
Yes please.
他人很帅  又风趣  他还
Okay. He's cute, he's funny, he's-
他还是个男的
He's a he?
是啊  天啊
Well yeah! ...Oh God.
我觉得
I-  just-  I thought-
很好  雪莉
Good, Shelley.
我要到厕所去把自己冲掉
I'm just gonna go flush myself down the toilet now...
再见
Okay, byebye...
听完后我都没心情吃面了
...Couldn't enjoy a cup of noodles after that.
多荒谬啊
I mean, is that ridiculous?
你能相信她竟然有这种想法吗
Can you believe she actually thought that?
能啊  好吧
Um... yeah.
我是说  第一次见到你时  你知道的
Well, I mean, when I first met you, you know,
我以为也许  没准儿  你可能是
I thought maybe, possibly, you might be...
真的吗
You did?
对  但后来你在菲比的生日会上
Yeah, but then you spent Phoebe's entire birthday party
一直盯着我的胸部  我想你大概不是吧
talking to my breasts, so then I figured maybe not.
那么
Huh. Did, uh...
你们第一次看见我时也是这样认为的吗
any of the rest of you guys think that when you first met me?
我是
I did.
-我不觉得  -我也是
- Not me. -  No no, me neither.
不过  上大学时
Although, uh, you know, back in college,
苏珊·赛德勒觉得你是
Susan Sallidor did.
开什么玩笑
You're kidding!
-你有告诉她我不是吗  -没有
- Did you tell her I wasn't? - No.
没有  只是因为  我也想跟她约会
No, it's just because, uh, I kinda wanted to go out with her too,
所以我告诉她
so I told her, actually,
你和伯尼·斯佩尔曼是一对
you were seeing Bernie Spellman...
那家伙也喜欢她  所以
who also liked her, so...
这简直是太神奇了
Well, this is fascinating.
那么  为什么这么认为
So, uh, what is it about me?
我不知道
I don't know,
因为你既聪明又风趣
because you're smart, you're funny...
罗斯也是聪明又风趣
Ross is smart and funny,
你们有想过他是吗
do you ever think that about him?
到底是为什么
What is it!
我也说不上来
Okay, I- I don't know,
但你就是有那种气质
you- you just-  you have a quality.
-没错  -绝对的  气质
- Yes. - Absolutely. A quality.
气质  说得好
Oh, oh, a quality, good,
我还担心你们看不出呢
because I was worried you guys were gonna be vague about this.
喂喂
Hello? Hello?
瑞秋  保罗从罗马打来的
Oh! Rachel, it's Paolo calling from Rome.
天啊  从罗马打来
Oh my God! Calling from Rome!
他从罗马打来电话哟
So he's calling from Rome.
我也可以
I could do that.
我到罗马去就是了
Just gotta go to Rome.
莫妮卡  你爸打来了
Monica, your dad just beeped in,
你能长话短说吗
but can you make it quick?
罗马的电话  我正和罗马通电话
Talking to Rome. I'm talking to Rome.
爸  怎么了
Hey dad, what's up?
我的天
Oh God.
罗斯  是外婆
Ross, it's Nana.
她的情况如何
So, uh, how's she doing?
医生说只剩几小时了
The doctor says it's a matter of hours.
-妈你还好吧  -我  我还好
- How- how are you, Mom? - Me? I'm fine, fine.
真高兴你们能来
I'm glad you're here. ...
-你的头发怎么了  -什么
- What's with your hair? - What?
-哪里变样了  -没有吧
- What's different? - Nothing.
或许是这个缘故
Oh, maybe that's it.
她真是令人难以置信  咱们的妈妈
She is unbelievable, our mother is...
好啦  放松点
Okay, relax, relax.
看来我们得在这儿待一段时间了
We are gonna be here for a while, it looks like,
免不了还要谈你男友和工作的事
and we still have boyfriends and your career to cover.
我的老天
Oh God!
她皮包里有发霉的钱币
The fuzzy little mints at the bottom of her purse.
真呕心
Oh! ...Yeah, they were gross.
你们知道我喜欢什么吗
Oh, you know what I loved?
她的代糖
Her Sweet 'n' Los.
她总是从餐厅里偷走代糖
How she was always stealing them from-  from restaurants.
不只是餐厅  我们家也一样
Not just restaurants, from our house.
盖勒太太
Mrs. Geller?
她看起来好小
She looks so small.
我知道
I know.
至少她能和外公还有菲丽丝姑姑团聚了
Well, at least she's with Pop- Pop and Aunt Phyllis now.
别了  外婆
Good bye, Nana.
再见  外婆
Bye, Nana.
罗斯
Ross!
护士
Nurse
怎么了
What is going on?!
护士说外婆已过世了是吧
Y'know how- how the nurse said that- that Nana had passed?
实际上不是
Well, she's not, quite..
-什么  -她还没有去世
- What? - She's not-past,
她还健在  她复活了
she's present, she's back.
怎么回事
What's going on?
-她可能已经死了  -她可能已经死了
- She may have died. - She may have died?
我们正在调查
We're looking into it.
我进去看看
I, uh, I'll go see.
这种事几乎不可能发生
This almost never happens!
现在她过世了
Now she's passed.
我必须要知道
I just have to know,
好吧  是因为我的头发吗
okay. Is it my hair?
对  钱德勒  就是因为你的头发
Yes, Chandler, that's exactly what it is. It's your hair.
你有一头同性恋一样的头发
Yeah, you have homosexual hair.
她怎么样了
So, um, did she...
两次
Twice.
Twice?
太糟糕了
Oh, that sucks!
你们还好吧
You guys okay?
说不上来  好诡异
I don't know, it's weird. I mean,
我知道她已过世  但我感觉
I know she's gone, but I just don't feel, uh...
或许是因为她还没有真的走
Maybe that's because she's not really gone.
不  她已经走了
Nono, she's gone.
我们检查了
We checked.
好多遍
A lot.
也许人们并不会真正离开
Hm, I mean maybe no- one ever really goes.
自从我妈妈去世后  不管是过去还是现在
Ever since my mom died, every now and then,
我都感觉她好像就在我附近
I get the feeling that she's like right here, you know?
还有黛比  我中学时最好的朋友
Oh! And Debbie, my best friend from junior high-
打迷你高尔夫的时候被闪电击中了
got struck by lightning on a miniature golf course-
每当我用那个黄色的小铅笔的时候
I always get this really strong Debbie vibe
我就会有一种很强烈的感觉
whenever I use one of those little yellow pencils, you know?
我好想念她
I miss her.
菲比  你要吗
Aw. Hey, Pheebs, want this?
谢谢
Thanks!
不客气  早上刚削好的
Sure. I just sharpened her this morning.
其实啊  这些我一点都不信
Now, see, I don't believe any of that.
我觉得一个人一旦死了  那就是死了
I think once you're dead, you're dead!
消失了  成了昆虫的食物
You're gone! You're worm food!
钱德勒像同性恋哈
...So Chandler looks gay, huh?
跟你说啊  我不知道这是谁
You know, I don't who this is,
但这绝对不是黛比
but it's not Debbie.
我以为要用密封的棺木
I thought it was gonna be a closed casket.
这并不代表她不能看起来体面一点
Well, that doesn't mean she can't look nice!
宝贝  你觉得你能进到里面去吗
Sweetie, you think you can get in there?
我想应该不会进不去吧
I don't see why not.
我的牙箍在这里
Here's my retainer!
-我在想  我走的时候  -爸
- I was just thinking. When my time comes- - Dad!
听我说
Listen to me!
我走的时候
When my time comes,
我想要海葬
I wanna be buried at sea.
什么
You what?
我要海葬
I wanna be buried at sea,
那一定很好玩
it looks like fun.
好玩是什么意思
Define fun.
那一天你们会玩得很开心的
Come on, you'll make a day of it!
你们可以租一条船  带着午餐
You'll rent a boat, pack a lunch...
然后把你的尸体丢入大海
...And then we throw your body in the water...
好像是有点好玩
Gee, that does sound fun.
每个人都自认为了解我
Everyone thinks they know me.
他们都说杰克·盖勒  跟我想的一样
Everyone says 'Jack Geller, so predictable'.
或许我像那样离世
Maybe after I'm gone,
他们会说  海葬  哎哟
they'll say 'Buried at sea! Huh!'.
他们大概会这么说吧
That's probably what they'll say.
希望如此
I'd like that.
美女
Hey, gorgeous.
听我说  昨天的事真的很抱歉  我
Hey. Look, I'm sorry about yesterday, I, um-
不  不用  不用担心
No, nono, don't-  don't worry about it.
相信我  显然别人也犯了相同的错误
Believe me, apparently other people have made the same mistake.
好的  唉
Oh! Okay! Phew!
那么  你为什么会觉得我是那样
So, uh... what do you think it is about me?
你就是有那种
I don't know, uh... you just have a- a...
调调  是哦
...Quality, right, great.
真可惜  因为你和罗尔本来很登对
You know, it's a shame, because you and Lowell would have made a great couple.
罗尔  会计部的罗尔
Lowell? Financial Services' Lowell,
你觉得我们很配
that's who you saw me with?
怎么了  他很帅啊
What? He's cute!
怎么不是负责发薪水的那个布莱恩啊
yeah... not Brian in Payroll.
难道你和布莱恩
Is Brian...?
没有  我不知道
No! Uh, I d'know!
重点是  如果你想替我和某人牵线
The point is, if you were gonna set me up with someone,
我不想你给我找像他那样的人
I'd like to think you'd set me up with someone like him.
我觉得你有点配不上布莱恩
Well, I think Brian's a little out of your league.
什么
Excuse me?
你觉得我配不上布莱恩
You don't think I could get a Brian?
其实我可以的
Because I could get a Brian.
相信我
Believe you me. ...
其实我不行
I'm really not.
这一件
This one?
不
No.
我已经给你们看过所有的衣服了
I have shown you everything we have.
除非你们希望你们的母亲穿着
Unless you want your mother to
柠檬黄套装过下辈子  还是选紫红色吧
spend eternity in a lemon yellow pant- suit, go with the burgundy.
不管咱们选什么
You know, whatever we pick,
她都会告诉咱们选错了
she would've told us it's the wrong one.
你说得没错  就选紫红色吧
You're right. We'll go with the burgundy.
选得好  我要出来了
Oh! A fine choice. I'm coming out.
等等  还缺鞋子
Wait! We need shoes!
好
Okay!
这一双如何
Um, how about these?
那是日装鞋子
That's really a day shoe.
难道她要去的地方  别人穿戴都很讲究吗
And where she's going everyone else will be dressier?
能找鞋跟细一点的鞋吗
Could we see something in a slimmer heel?
这里没有和紫红衣服配套的晚装鞋
Okay, I have nothing in an evening shoe in the burgundy.
也许能试试看这个银色的
I can show you something in a silver that may work.
不行  一定要紫红色
No, it really should be burgundy.
除非咱们选其他衣服
Mm. Unless we go with a different dress?
不  等等
No! Nonono, wait a sec.
我看看后面或许有
I may have something in the back.
天呀
Oh my God..
你没事吧  亲爱的
Is everything all right, dear?
没事  只是外婆的东西
Yeah, just... just Nana stuff.
早  准备好了没
How we doing, you guys ready?
妈妈早上打电话提醒我不要扎头发
Mom already called this morning to remind me not to wear my hair up.
你知道我的耳朵并最好看的地方吗
Did you know my ears are not my best feature?
有时候我也这样想
Some days it's all I can think about.
抱歉  我迟到了
Hi, sorry I'm late,
我找不到我的"耳圈"
I couldn't find my bearings.
你是指你的耳环
Oh, you- you mean your earrings?
我刚说什么
What'd I say?
你穿这一双
Are these the shoes?
对  保罗从意大利寄来的
Yes. Paolo sent them from Italy.
难道咱们这里没有鞋子卖么
What, we- uh-  we don't have shoes here, or...?
早安  准备走了没
Morning. We ready to go?
穿戴整齐后   我们不是都好看许多
Well, don't we look nice all dressed up?...
人模人样的  对吧
It's stuff like that, isn't it?
刚刚的仪式真好
It was a really beautiful service.
可不是吗
It really was.
过来心肝
Oh, come here, sweetheart.
你知道吗
You know,
我觉得你应该开始使用晚霜了
I think it might be time for you to start using night cream.
怎么了
What?
没什么  你的外套听上去很像
Nothing, just your overcoat sounds
布莱登·马斯伯格
remarkably like Brent Mussberger.
瞧  巨人队对牛仔队
Check it out, Giants- Cowboys.
你在葬礼上看足球比赛
You're watching a football game at a funeral?
不  是预赛
No, it's the pre- game.
我准备在招待会上看正式比赛
I'm gonna watch it at the reception.
你真是个很可怕很可怕的人
You are a frightening, frightening man.
不  保罗送我的新鞋
Oh no! My new Paolo shoes!
希望没坏
Oh, I hope they're not ruined.
多美好的一天啊
God, what a great day. ...
怎么了  我是指天气
What? Weather- wise!
知道  空气啊  树木啊
I know, uh, the air, the- the trees...
即使外婆已过世
even though Nana's gone there's,
几乎就好像  我不知道  生命
there's something almost, uh-  I don't , almost life- aff-
天哪  罗斯
God! Ross!
我没事
I'm fine.
只是  我最大的梦魇终于成真
Just- just... having my worst fear realised...
别担心
Okay, don't worry,
我只是看看你有没有抽筋
I'm just checking to see if the muscle's in spasm...huh.
怎么了  怎么回事
What, what is it?
你的皮带穿孔掉了一个
You missed a belt loop.
对了  正在抽筋
Okay, it's in spasm.
过来  孩子
Here, sweetie, here.
我打高尔夫受伤时都用这个
I took these when I had my golfing accident.
妈  谢谢
Mom thanks.
抱歉  我叫安朵拉  桃乐丝的女儿
Sorry-  Hi, I'm Andrea. I'm Dorothy's daughter.
我叫钱德勒  我不知道桃乐丝是谁
Hi, I'm Chandler, and I have no idea who Dorothy is.
看看  谁起来了
Hey, look who's up!
感觉如何
How do you feel?
感觉好多了
I feel great.
我觉得  很好
I feel-  great, I feel great.
那些药可真有效呢
Wow, those pills really worked, huh?
对  头两颗没什么用  但是后来的两颗
Not the first two, but the second two-  woooo! ...
我爱你们大家
I love you guys.
你们是最棒的
You guys are the greatest.
我爱我的妹妹
I love my sister,
我爱菲比
I love Pheebs...
钱德勒
...Chandler!
我爱你伙计
I love you, man.
听着  如果你想当同志  就当吧
And listen, man, if you wanna be gay, be gay.
我不在乎
Doesn't matter to me.
你说得对
You were right.
瑞秋  瑞秋  瑞秋
Rachel. Rachel Rachel.
我最爱你了
I do love you the most.
-哦  你知道我最爱谁吗  -不
- Oh, you know who I love the most? - No.
你
You.
我不懂
Oh.. you don't get it!
你在干吗呢
What do you got there?
我  这是助听器
Just a, uh... hearing disability.
比数多少
What's the score?
巨人队以17比14领先
Seventeen- fourteen Giants...
第三场还有三分钟
three minutes to go in the third.
好极了
Beautiful!
菲比  能拿块饼干给我吗
Pheebs, could you maybe hand me a cracker?
你外婆一定不喜欢的
Your grandmother would have hated this.
当然  这是她的葬礼
Well, sure, what with it being her funeral and all.
不  我听到的全部是
No, I'd be hearing about
"为什么没有蜜饯火腿"
'Why didn't I get the honey- glazed ham?'
或是"我买的花不够贵"之类的话
I didn't spend enough on flowers,
如果我买更贵的花  她又会说
and if I spent more she'd be saying
"何必花那么多钱  我不需要花
'Why are you wasting your money? I don't need flowers,
我已经死了"
I'm dead'.
像外婆的作风
That sounds like Nana.
你知道和一个对你事无巨细都喋喋不休的人
Do you know what it's like to grow up
一起生活成长是什么滋味吗
with someone who is critical of every single thing you say?
我可以想像
...I can imagine.
告诉你
I'm telling you,
你妈我能最后变成一个乐观积极
it's a wonder your mother turned out to be the positive,
健康向上的人  真是个奇迹
life- affirming person that she is.
真是个奇迹
That is a wonder.
那么跟我说说  妈妈
So tell me something, Mom.
如果可以重来
If you had to do it all over again,
如果她现在就在这里
I mean, if she was here right now,
你会告诉她吗
would you tell her?
告诉她什么
Tell her what?
她如何使你抓狂
How she drove you crazy,
挑剔每一件事
picking on every little detail
例如  你的头发
like your hair... for example.
我不懂你在说什么
I'm not sure I know what you're getting at.
你不觉得如果大家能开诚布公地谈谈
Do you think things would have been better
事情会有所好转吗
if you'd just told her the truth?
不认为
...No.
我觉得有些事还是不说更好一点
I think some things are better left unsaid.
家和万事兴  这样大家才更容易相处
I think it's nicer when people just get along.
还要酒吗  亲爱的
More wine, dear?
哦  再来点
Oh, I think so.
你戴这副耳环真好看
Those earrings look really lovely on you.
谢谢  你给我的
Thank you. They're yours.
其实是外婆的
Actually they were Nana's.
实在是太沮丧了
Now I'm depressed! ...
比刚才还沮丧
Even more than I was.
这个光屁股的小男孩是谁
Hey, who's this little naked guy?
那个光屁股小男孩就是我
That little naked guy would be me.
瞧那个小东西
Aww, look at the little thing.
对  那是我的小弟弟
Yes, yes, fine, that is my penis.
成熟点行吗
Can we be grown- ups now?
那些人是谁
Who are those people?
可把我问倒了
Got me.
是外婆  中间那一个
Oh, that's Nana, right there in the middle.
我看看
Let me see
我和大伙摄于在爪哇  乔家
'Me and the gang at Java Joe's'.
莫妮卡  你和你外婆长得一模一样
Wow, Monica, you look just like your grandmother.
当时她几岁
How old was she there?
1939年
Let's see, 1939...
24或25岁
yeah, 24, 25?
他们好像玩得很开心
Looks like a fun gang.
看  光屁股的莫妮卡
Ooh, look- look- look- look- look! I got Monica naked!
不  还是我
Nono, that would be me again.
我在尝试新事物
I'm, uh, just trying something.
罗威
Hey, Lowell.
钱德勒
Hey, Chandler.
会计部最近还好吧
So how's it going there in Financial Services?
就好像没有吉祥物的狂欢节
It's like Mardi Gras without the paper mache heads.
你呢
How about you?
很好  听着
Good, good.  Listen, heh,
我不知道雪莉如何对你说我这个人
I don't know what Shelley told you about me,
但是  我不是的
but, uh... I'm not.
我知道  我也是这样告诉她的
I know. That's what I told her.
真的
Really?
你看得出来
So-  you can tell?
十之八九
Pretty much, most of the time.
我们有某种雷达似的气场
We have a kind of... radar.
这么说你认为  我没那种调调
So you don't think I have a, a quality?
作为我们这样的人
Speaking for my people,
我得说没有
I'd have to say no.
对了  你的朋友
By the way, your friend
负责发薪水的布莱恩  他是
Brian from Payroll, he is.
他是
He is?
对  而且你配不上他
Yup, and way out of your league.
我配不上他
Out of my league.
我可以征服布莱恩
I can get a Brian,
如果我想要布莱恩  我就能得到他
If I wanted to get a Brian, I could get a Brian.
你好  布莱恩
Hey, Brian.